Hello English learners, welcome back to EnglishPod.
英语学习者你们好，欢迎回到EnglishPod。
My name is Marco.
我是Marco。
And I'm Erika.
我是Erika。
And today we're bringing you another lesson on our sports series.
今天我们要为大家带来体育系列的另一节课。
We're talking about baseball today.
我们今天要聊的是棒球。
Baseball, the American national pastime.
棒球，美国的国民消遣。
Is it?
是吗？
Yes, it is.
是的，没错。
Okay.
好的。
So we're going to be looking at this interesting sport that is played mainly in the Caribbean
所以我们要看看这项主要在加勒比地区进行的趣味运动，
and well, it's actually very popular in the United States and Japan.
而且，它在美国和日本其实非常流行。
That's right.
没错。
Korea.
还有韩国。
Yep.
是的。
And we're going to learn a bunch of baseball language, but we're also going to see how
我们要学习一堆棒球术语，但也要看看
baseball has a big influence on English in general.
棒球对英语整体有多大影响。
That's right.
没错。
So we're going to learn a lot of great things today.
所以今天我们要学很多很棒的东西。
So why don't we start and listen to our dialogue?
那我们开始听对话吧？
Hello baseball fans and welcome back to today's game.
棒球迷们你们好，欢迎回到今天的比赛。
My name is Rick Fields and of course I am here once again with the man that seals the
我是Rick Fields，当然，我再次和那位能搞定一切的人
deal Bob Copeland.
Bob Copeland一起在这里。
It's a beautiful day to see two world-class teams face each other and fight for their
今天是个好天气，能看到两支世界级球队面对面交锋，为
right to be called champions.
被称为冠军的权利而战。
Well, the national anthem has just been sung and the umpire has started the game.
嗯，国歌刚刚唱完，裁判已经开始了比赛。
It's time to play ball.
是时候开球了。
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
Roger Vargas上场击球。
Pitcher winds up and strike one.
投手挥臂，好球一。
Very nice curve ball by the pitcher.
投手投了一个非常漂亮的曲线球。
The catcher gives him the sign.
捕手给他打暗号。
He winds up and Vargas gets a line drive.
他挥臂，Vargas打出一个平飞球。
The players are scrambling to get the ball.
球员们正在争抢球。
Vargas gets to first base and he's still going.
Vargas上了一垒，他还在继续跑。
The outfielder throws it to second.
外野手把球扔向二垒。
Vargas slides.
Vargas滑垒。
He's safe.
他安全上垒。
Great play.
好球。
We have a runner on third and up at bat is Brian Okami.
我们三垒有跑垒员，上场击球的是Brian Okami。
There's the pitch.
球投出来了。
He hits it.
他击中了。
It's going, going.
球在飞，在飞。
That ball is gone.
球飞出去了。
Home run by Okami.
Okami打出全垒打。
That puts this team ahead by two as we are at the bottom of the fifth inning here at
这让这支队伍领先两分，现在我们是在第五局下半局，
Ritchie Stadium.
在Ritchie体育场。
All right.
好的。
Well, a pretty exciting game there at Ritchie Stadium.
嗯，Ritchie体育场的比赛相当精彩。
Exactly.
没错。
And we have some interesting players, Roger Vargas and Brian Okami.
我们有一些有趣的球员，Roger Vargas和Brian Okami。
All right.
好的。
So well, we saw some great words and well, it's time for us to take a look at them now
那么，我们看到了一些很棒的词，现在是时候在“语言要点”环节
in Language Takeaway.
仔细看看它们了。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
Okay.
好的。
We're going to look at some common sports and baseball words here.
我们要看一些常见的体育和棒球词汇。
Now, the first phrase, we'll hear this almost at any sort of international sports event,
第一个短语，我们几乎在任何国际体育赛事中都能听到，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
And it's the national anthem.
就是国歌。
National anthem.
国歌。
So, this is a song, right?
所以，这是一首歌，对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
It's the song that you sing about your country and many people confuse it, right?
这是你唱关于自己国家的歌，很多人会搞混，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
A lot of people might say national hymn.
很多人可能会说“national hymn”。
Okay.
好的。
Because in some languages, it might be like a hymn, like literally translating.
因为在某些语言里，它可能像赞美诗，字面翻译过来。
Yeah.
是的。
But in English, it's called the national anthem.
但在英语里，它叫“national anthem”。
The national anthem.
国歌。
All right.
好的。
So, what about our next word?
那下一个词呢？
Well, we were talking about the pitcher.
嗯，我们刚才在说投手。
Pitcher.
投手。
P-I-T-C-H-E-R.
P-I-T-C-H-E-R。
The pitcher.
投手。
Pitcher.
Okay.
好的。
And now, this is one of the players on the baseball team and his job is to?
这是棒球队里的一个球员，他的工作是？
To throw the ball.
投球。
To throw the ball really fast.
把球投得很快。
So that the guy can hit it with the bat.
这样击球手才能用球棒击球。
Okay.
好的。
So, that's the pitcher.
那就是投手。
Now, the interesting thing is that the baseball commentator said the pitcher winds up.
有趣的是，棒球解说员说投手“winds up”。
Winds up.
挥臂。
To wind up.
Okay.
好的。
Well, let me paint you a picture.
嗯，让我给你描述一下。
Okay.
好的。
So, imagine a clock.
想象一个钟。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And you're turning, turning, and turning the clock to wind it up, to get it ready to go.
你不停地转、转、转，给钟上发条，让它准备好运行。
To make it work.
让它工作起来。
Exactly.
没错。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And the pitcher is doing the same sort of thing, bringing his arm back behind him, getting
投手也在做类似的事，把手臂向后拉，
ready to throw the ball.
准备投球。
Okay.
好的。
So, that is to wind up.
那就是“to wind up”。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Very good.
非常好。
So, you can use this word not only in baseball, but for other things that require you to do
所以这个词不仅可以用在棒球里，还可以用在其他需要你做
this action.
这个动作的事情上。
Right.
对。
To turn something and get it ready to have lots of power.
转动某物，让它准备好产生很大力量。
Like some toys.
比如一些玩具。
Yeah.
是的。
Or maybe like a music box.
或者像音乐盒。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Okay.
好的。
Wind up.
挥臂。
What about our next phrase?
那下一个短语呢？
Well, Roger Vargas hit a line drive.
嗯，Roger Vargas打了一个平飞球。
Line drive.
平飞球。
Okay.
好的。
So, what is a line drive?
那什么是平飞球？
Well, it's a term from baseball.
嗯，这是棒球术语。
And when you hit a line drive, you hit the ball sort of low on towards the ground, and
当你打出一个平飞球时，你击球比较低，朝向地面，
it travels along the outside of the field.
球沿着场地外侧飞行。
Right.
对。
So, the ball basically travels along the foul line.
所以球基本上是沿着边线飞。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
That white line.
那条白线。
The white line.
白线。
Yeah.
是的。
Exactly.
没错。
Very good.
非常好。
So, that's a line drive.
那就是平飞球。
And so, the players on the field were scrambling to get the ball.
然后场上的球员在争抢球。
Scrambling.
争抢。
Now, we know scrambled eggs from one of our lessons.
我们从之前的一节课里知道了“scrambled eggs”。
Yes.
是的。
But the verb to scramble means to move quickly in a disorganized way to do something.
但动词“to scramble”意思是快速、混乱地移动去做某事。
Okay.
好的。
So, the players are moving very fast, trying to get the ball, but they're not doing it
所以球员们移动得很快，试图拿到球，但做得
very well.
不太有条理。
Right.
对。
And you can use this in other ways, right?
这个词也可以用在其他方面，对吧？
Not just in baseball.
不只是棒球里。
Right.
对。
For example, we can say, the people are scrambling to buy their tickets for the concert.
比如，我们可以说，人们争相购买演唱会的票。
Yeah.
是的。
Or, I'm going on vacation tomorrow and I'm scrambling to get everything ready.
或者，我明天要去度假，我正在手忙脚乱地准备一切。
Exactly.
没错。
It's a very good term that you can use also in your daily life.
这是一个很好的词，你在日常生活中也能用。
Exactly.
没错。
All right.
好的。
And what about our last word for today on Language Takeaway?
那今天“语言要点”的最后一个词呢？
Well, they were in the fifth inning of the game.
嗯，比赛进行到第五局。
Okay.
好的。
So, inning.
所以，“局”。
Inning.
局。
All right.
好的。
This is another baseball term.
这是另一个棒球术语。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
And it just means the period of play.
它就是指比赛的一个时段。
Okay.
好的。
So, we learned, for example, that in soccer you have two halves.
我们学到，比如，足球有上下半场。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Or, in hockey, you have three periods.
或者，冰球有三节。
All right.
好的。
And in baseball, you have nine innings.
而在棒球里，有九局。
Okay.
好的。
Great.
很棒。
So, some interesting sports and baseball vocabulary.
所以是一些有趣的体育和棒球词汇。
Now, I think it'll help us to hear this again slower.
现在，我觉得再慢速听一遍对话会帮助我们理解。
So, let's listen to the dialogue.
那我们听对话吧。
Hello, baseball fans, and welcome back to today's game.
棒球迷们你们好，欢迎回到今天的比赛。
My name is Rick Fields, and of course, I am here once again with the man that seals the
我是Rick Fields，当然，我再次和那位能搞定一切的人
deal, Bob Copeland.
Bob Copeland一起在这里。
It's a beautiful day to see two world-class teams face each other and fight for their
今天是个好天气，能看到两支世界级球队面对面交锋，为
right to be called champions.
被称为冠军的权利而战。
Well, the national anthem has just been sung, and the umpire has started the game.
嗯，国歌刚刚唱完，裁判已经开始了比赛。
It's time to play ball.
是时候开球了。
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
Roger Vargas上场击球。
The pitcher winds up and strike one.
投手挥臂，好球一。
A very nice curveball by the pitcher.
投手投了一个非常漂亮的曲线球。
The catcher gives him the sign.
捕手给他打暗号。
He winds up, and Vargas gets a line drive.
他挥臂，Vargas打出一个平飞球。
The players are scrambling to get the ball.
球员们正在争抢球。
Vargas gets to first base, and he's still going.
Vargas上了一垒，他还在继续跑。
The outfielder throws it to second.
外野手把球扔向二垒。
Vargas slides.
Vargas滑垒。
He's safe.
他安全上垒。
Great play.
好球。
We have a runner on third, and up at bat is Brian Okami.
我们三垒有跑垒员，上场击球的是Brian Okami。
There's the pitch.
球投出来了。
He hits it.
他击中了。
It's going, going.
球在飞，在飞。
That ball is gone.
球飞出去了。
Home run by Okami.
Okami打出全垒打。
That puts this team ahead by two, as we are at the bottom of the fifth inning here at
这让这支队伍领先两分，现在我们是在第五局下半局，
Ritchie Stadium.
在Ritchie体育场。
All right, so as we said, there are a lot of English terms that come from baseball,
好的，就像我们说的，很多英语术语来自棒球，
but we use them in business context or in your daily life, right?
但我们在商业场合或日常生活中也会用到它们，对吧？
Yeah, why don't we look at those now in Fluency Builder.
好，我们不如现在就在流利度训练中看看这些。
Fluency Builder.
流利度训练。
All right, so the first phrase that we have is, up to bat.
好的，我们第一个短语是，轮到上场。
Up to bat.
轮到上场。
So literally, in this dialogue, it means the guy is standing on home plate, ready to hit
所以字面上，在这个对话中，它意味着那个人站在本垒板上，准备击球，
the ball, right?
对吧？
Right.
对。
He has the bat, and he's ready to hit it.
他拿着球棒，准备击球。
But what about in other contexts?
但在其他语境中呢？
So for example, you can be at a meeting, and maybe it's your turn to talk.
比如，你在开会，可能轮到你发言了。
So you're up to bat.
所以你就轮到上场了。
So exactly.
没错。
Your boss will say, okay, Erica, you're up to bat.
你的老板会说，好的，Erica，轮到你了。
Okay, so it means sort of like it's your turn.
好的，所以它有点像轮到你了。
It's your turn.
轮到你了。
Yeah.
嗯。
Very good.
很好。
All right, so that's another term that is used in baseball, but very commonly used in
好的，所以这是另一个棒球术语，但在其他场合也很常用。
other circumstances.
其他场合。
So we also saw in the dialogue that Roger Vegas, he hit the ball, but he missed, and
我们在对话中也看到，Roger Vegas 击球了，但他没击中，那是第一击。
that was strike one.
第一击。
Right.
对。
Strike one.
第一击。
So in baseball, you have three strikes.
在棒球中，你有三次击球机会。
Three tries.
三次尝试。
Three tries before you're out.
三次尝试后你就出局了。
Yes.
是的。
And so now, the same thing happens in daily life.
现在，同样的事情也发生在日常生活中。
So if someone says, that was strike one.
所以如果有人说了，那是第一击。
It means you made the first mistake.
意思是你犯了第一个错误。
Yes.
是的。
And if you make two more, you will be fired, for example.
如果你再犯两次，你就会被解雇，比如。
Or maybe your parents will say, okay, that wasn't nice.
或者你的父母会说，好吧，那不太友好。
Strike one.
第一击。
And then two more times, and you'll have a timeout.
然后再两次，你就要被罚暂停。
Or you'll be grounded.
或者你会被禁足。
Yes.
是的。
Okay, so that's also called a strike.
好的，所以这也叫一击。
And the pitcher threw a curve ball.
投手投了一个曲线球。
A curve ball.
曲线球。
Curve ball.
So, okay, pretty clear.
所以，好吧，挺清楚的。
A curve ball is when you throw the ball, and it sort of goes in a curve.
曲线球就是你投球时，球会走曲线。
It doesn't go straight, right?
它不会直着走，对吧？
Right.
对。
Exactly.
没错。
But how can this be used outside of baseball?
但这怎么用在棒球之外呢？
So you can say, oh, my boss threw me a curve ball today.
所以你可以说，哦，我老板今天给我投了个曲线球。
So he gave you an unexpected problem.
所以他给了你一个意想不到的问题。
Uh-huh.
嗯哼。
Or something that was difficult to handle.
或者一些难以处理的事情。
Okay.
好的。
This one is pretty interesting.
这个挺有趣的。
We'd like to hear a few more examples.
我们想听更多例子。
Example one.
例子一。
My boss threw me a curve ball today, so I have to stay and work late.
我老板今天给我投了个曲线球，所以我得留下来加班。
Example two.
例子二。
It was a huge curve ball when she asked me how many kids I wanted to have.
她问我想要几个孩子时，那真是个巨大的曲线球。
How am I supposed to know?
我怎么会知道？
All right, so that's basically a curve ball.
好的，所以基本上这就是曲线球。
You can say an unexpected problem or situation.
你可以说是一个意想不到的问题或情况。
That's right.
没错。
And our last phrase, and probably one that you already know, home run.
我们最后一个短语，可能你已经知道了，本垒打。
A home run.
本垒打。
From baseball, we know that that's when you hit the ball really far.
从棒球中，我们知道那是你把球打得很远。
And you hit it outside of the playing area, outside the park.
你把它打出比赛区域，打出球场。
Yes.
是的。
And now if you use it in a business context or in your daily life.
现在如果你在商业语境或日常生活中使用它。
It means something similar.
它意味着类似的东西。
Why don't we take a listen to the examples and see if we can figure it out.
我们不如听听例子，看看能不能理解。
Example one.
例子一。
Great job on that sales presentation.
那个销售演示做得很好。
You really hit a home run.
你真的打了个本垒打。
Example two.
例子二。
Our sales team hit a home run this month by doubling our revenue.
我们这个月的销售团队通过收入翻倍打了个本垒打。
Okay, so basically a home run is a success.
好的，所以基本上本垒打就是成功。
A victory.
胜利。
Yeah, something, a big accomplishment.
嗯，一个巨大的成就。
That's right.
没错。
So we've seen a lot of these great phrases.
所以我们看到了很多这些好短语。
And as you can see, a lot of them from baseball are used in your daily life.
正如你所见，很多来自棒球的短语都用在日常生活中。
And there are many, many more.
而且还有很多很多。
Okay, well, why don't we hear them again in the baseball context.
好的，我们不如在棒球语境中再听一遍。
And we'll listen to the dialogue one more time.
我们再听一遍对话。
Hello baseball fans and welcome back to today's game.
大家好，棒球迷们，欢迎回到今天的比赛。
My name is Rick Fields and of course I am here once again with the man that seals the
我是 Rick Fields，当然，我再次和那位能搞定一切的人 Bob Copeland 在一起。
deal Bob Copeland.
搞定一切的人 Bob Copeland。
It's a beautiful day to see two world class teams face each other and fight for their
今天天气很好，可以看到两支世界级球队对决，为他们的冠军头衔而战。
right to be called champions.
为他们的冠军头衔而战。
Well, the national anthem has just been sung and the umpire has started the game.
好了，国歌刚刚唱完，裁判开始了比赛。
It's time to play ball.
是时候开球了。
Roger Vargas is up at bat.
Roger Vargas 轮到上场。
Pitcher winds up and strike one.
投手挥臂，第一击。
Very nice curve ball by the pitcher.
投手投了一个很漂亮的曲线球。
The catcher gives him the sign.
接球手给他信号。
He winds up and Vargas gets a line drive.
他挥臂，Vargas 打了一个平直球。
The players are scrambling to get the ball.
球员们正在争抢球。
Vargas gets to first base and he's still going.
Vargas 跑到一垒，他还在继续。
The outfielder throws it to second.
外野手把球扔到二垒。
Vargas slides.
Vargas 滑垒。
He's safe.
他安全上垒。
Great play.
好球。
We have a runner on third and up at bat is Brian Okami.
我们有一个跑垒员在三垒，轮到上场的是 Brian Okami。
There's the pitch.
投球来了。
He hits it.
他击中了。
It's going, going.
球在飞，在飞。
That ball is gone.
那个球飞出去了。
Home run by Okami.
Okami 的本垒打。
That puts this team ahead by two as we are at the bottom of the fifth inning here at
这让这支队伍领先两分，现在是在 Ritchie 体育场的第五局下半场。
Ritchie Stadium.
Ritchie 体育场。
All right.
好的。
So an interesting dialogue, a very interesting sport.
所以一个有趣的对话，一项非常有趣的运动。
And well, personally, I never played this as a child.
嗯，就我个人而言，我小时候从没玩过这个。
Me neither, really.
我也没有，真的。
I don't really like it too much, but it is kind of fun to go to a game and especially
我不太喜欢它，但去现场看比赛还是挺好玩的，尤其是在美国，吃热狗什么的。
in the United States, have those hot dogs and all that.
吃热狗什么的。
OK, yeah.
好的，嗯。
Well, a cultural event, a really important piece of American culture.
嗯，一个文化活动，美国文化中非常重要的一部分。
Exactly.
没错。
So, well, we encourage you to come to our website, EnglishPod.com.
所以，嗯，我们鼓励你访问我们的网站 EnglishPod.com。
Tell us what you think.
告诉我们你的想法。
And also, of course, if you have questions or doubts, be sure to tell us.
当然，如果你有问题或疑问，一定要告诉我们。
If you have any other sort of baseball related phrases, let us know about them on the website.
如果你有其他棒球相关的短语，在网站上告诉我们。
OK, so we'll see you guys there.
好的，那我们到时候见。
Thanks for downloading.
感谢下载。
And until next time, goodbye.
下次再见，再见。
Bye.
再见。